Finding aid for Jesse Siddall Reeves Papers, 1853-1942
Bentley Historical Library
Jesse Siddall Reeves Papers
1853-1942
1901-1942
Bentley Historical Library
Reeves, Jesse Siddall, 1871-1942
86466 Aa 2; UAm
14 linear feet
1 oversize folder
Chairman of the department of political science at University of Michigan. Correspondence, reports, manuscript articles, book reviews, lecture notes, and miscellaneous papers concerning family affairs and his academic interests in political science and international law.
The collection came from the estate of Jesse S. Reeves in 1942 (Donor no. 1300 ); a smaller portion was the gift of Mr. Arthur Reeves (donor no. 3642 ) in 1960.
The collection is open to research.
Jesse S. Reeves, professor and chairman of the department of political science of the University of Michigan, was born January 27, 1872. He was student at Kenyon College in Ohio before graduating from Amherst College in 1891 with a B.S. He received his Ph.D. from Johns Hopkins University in 1894. He practiced law for a time before deciding on a career as an academic. He taught at Johns Hopkins (1905-06) and Dartmouth (1907-1910) before accepting a position as professor and chairman of the newly created department of political science at the University of Michigan in 1910. He held this position until his retirement in 1937. In 1931, he was appointed W.W. Cook professor of American institutions, which position he held until his automatic retirement from the faculty in February 1942.
Reeves was an authority on international law who was often called upon to serve on numerous commissions. For two years, beginning in 1925, he served as the American member of the Pan-American Commission of Jurists for the codification of international law. And in 1930, he was technical advisor to the American delegation to the Hague Conference for the Codification of International Law. Reeves was a member of various professional organizations and the author of books and articles in his area of expertise. Reeves died July 7, 1942.
The Reeves papers largely concern JSR's activities as professor (also chairman) of the University of Michigan Department of Political Science from his appointment in 1910 until his retirement in 1937. The great bulk of the collection consists of Reeves' correspondence. With this is a smaller series of such other materials as lectures, research materials, professional organizational materials. As an aid to accessing the correspondence, a selective index of correspondents and subjects has been prepared and is appended to the following containing listing.
Alpena (Mich.); Fascism.; International law.; Nicaragua -- Description and travel.; Panama -- Description and travel.; Panama Canal (Panama); Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1904.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1908.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1912.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1920.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1924.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1928.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1932.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1936.; Presidents -- United States -- Election -- 1940.; Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905.; Automobile travel -- United States.; Voyages and travels.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Education and the war.; World War, 1914-1918 -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor.; Camping -- 1911-1920.; Canoes.; Photographs.; International Commission on Jurists (1906); Reeves, Jesse Siddall, 1872-1942.; University of Michigan -- Buildings.; University of Michigan. School of Education.; University of Michigan. School of Dentistry.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Germanic Languages and Literatures.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Political Science.; University of Michigan. Engineering Research Institute.; University of Michigan. Institute of Public Administration.; University of Michigan. Library.; University of Michigan. President.; University of Michigan. Senate.; University of Michigan. University College.; American Association of University Professors.; American Political Science Association.; Kenyon College.; Michigan School of Religion.; Society for International Law.; Gomberg, Moses, 1866-1947.; Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952.; Reeves, Jesse Siddall, 1872-1942.; University of Michigan. Summer Session on International Law.; Van Tyne, Claude Halstead, 1869-1930.; Adams, Charles Francis, 1835-1915.; Adams, Randolph Greenfield, 1892-1951.; Anderson, William P., 1888-; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949.; Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937.; Bates, Henry Moore, 1869-1949.; Beakes, Samuel Willard, 1861-1927.; Beal, Junius E. (Junius Emery), 1860-1942.; Bemis, Samuel Flagg, 1891-1973.; Blakeslee, George Hubbard, 1871-1954.; Bonner, Campbell, 1876-; Borchard, Edwin Montefiore, 1884-1951.; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.; Brown, Everett Somerville, 1886-1964.; Brown, Philip Marshall, 1875-1966.; Brown, Prentiss M. (Prentiss Marsh), 1889-1973.; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925.; Burton, Marion Le Roy, 1874-1925.; Carr, Wilbur J. (Wilbur John), 1870-1942.; Clements, William L. (William Lawrence), 1861-1934.; Collier, William Miller, 1867-1956.; Comstock, William Alfred, 1877-1949.; Cooley, Charles Horton, 1864-1929.; Cooley, Mortimer E. (Mortimer Elwyn), 1855-1944.; Cooley, Thomas McIntyre, 1824-1898.; Corwin, Edward Samuel, 1878-1963.; Coudert, Frederic R. (Frederic René), 1871-; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Crane, Robert Treat, 1880-; D'Ooge, Martin Luther, 1839-1915.; Effinger, John R. (John Robert), 1869-1933.; Eggert, Carl Edgar, 1868-1944.; Farrand, Max, 1869-1945.; Field, Oliver Peter, 1897-1953.; Fite, Emerson David, 1874-1953.; Ford, Henry, 1863-1947.; Ford, Worthington Chauncey, 1858-1941.; Garfield, Harry Augustus, 1863-1942.; Garner, James Wilford, 1871-1938.; Gomberg, Moses, 1866-1947.; Guthe, Karl Eugen, 1866-1915.; Hart, Albert Bushnell, 1854-1943.; Hayden, Joseph Ralston, 1887-1945.; Hays, Will H. (Will Harrison), 1879-1954.; Hershey, Amos Shartle, 1867-1933.; Hinsdale, Mary L.; Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952.; Hudson, Manley O. (Manley Ottmer), 1886-1960.; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948.; Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955.; Huntington, E. V. (Edward Vermilye), 1874-1952.; Hutchins, Harry B. (Harry Burns), 1847-1930.; Jameson, J. Franklin (John Franklin), 1859-1937.; Johnson, Allan Chester, 1881-1955.; Kellogg, Frank B. (Frank Billings), 1856-1937.; Kelsey, Francis W. (Francis Willey), 1858-; Knudsen, William S., 1879-1948.; Koch, Theodore Wesley, 1871-1941.; Korff, S. A., Baron (Sergei Aleksandrovich), 1876-1924.; Korzybski, Alfred, 1879-1950.; Kraus, Edward Henry, 1875-1973.; Laski, Harold Joseph, 1893-1950.; Latane, John Holladay, 1869-1932.; Leacock, Stephen, 1869-1944.; Little, Clarence C. (Clarence Cook), 1888-; Lloyd, Alfred H. (Alfred Henry), 1864-1927.; McLaren, Walter Wallace.; McLaughlin, Andrew Cunningham, 1861-1947.; McLeod, Clarence John, 1895-1959.; Merriam, Charles Edward, 1874-1953.; Michener, Earl C. (Earl Cory), 1876-1957.; Munro, William Bennett, 1875-1957.; Murfin, James Orin, 1875-1940.; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.; Murrow, Edward R.; Newberry, Truman Handy, 1864-1945.; Ogg, Frederic Austin, 1878-1951.; Perkins, Dexter, 1889-; Pollock, James K. (James Kerr), 1898-1968.; Ray, P. Orman (Perley Orman), 1875-; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937.; Rowe, Leo S., 1871-1946.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Sanders, Henry A. (Henry Arthur), 1868-1956.; Sayre, Francis Bowes, 1885-1972.; Schmitt, Bernadotte Everly, 1886-1969.; Sforza, Carlo, Conte, 1872-1952.; Shotwell, James Thomson, 1874-1965.; Smith, Shirley Wheeler, 1875-1959.; Stone, Ralph, 1868-1956.; Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1882-1944.; Van Tyne, Claude Halstead, 1869-1930.; Vollenhaven, C. V.; Welles, Sumner, 1892-1961.; White, William Allen, 1868-1944.; Wickersham, George W. (George Woodward), 1858-1936.; Wilson, George Grafton, 1863-1951.; Winter, John Garrett, 1881-1956.; Wright, Quincy, 1890-1970.; Yntema, Hessel E.
- Correspondence and related papers
  Reeves' correspondence and related papers are arranged chronologically. It is subdivided into several time spans roughly reflecting major periods in Reeves' career: 1953-1912, 1913-1917, 1918,1919-1926, 1927-1942.
  - 1853-1912
    The papers for 1853-1912 consist largely of personal and family correspondence. Much of Reeves' correspondence is with his brother Will, professor of English at Kenyon College. Reeves made a trip to Panama and Nicaragua in 1897 and his letters home contain excellent descriptions of the construction of the canal. The negotiations relating to Reeves' acceptance of a position at the University of Michigan professorship will be found in the folder for March 1910.
    - 1853-1912, 33 folders (Box 1)
  - 1913-1917
    In addition to departmental information, the letters for 1913-1917 include family correspondence (mainly letters exchanged with his brother Will). There are also papers dealing with his association with the American Political Science Association. Of interest are letters detailing the reaction of the academic community to the First World War.
    - 1913-March 1914, 47 folders (Box 1)
    - April 1914-1917, 86 folders (Box 2)
  - 1918
    The 1918 papers here deal almost exclusively with Reeves' service as a captain in the United States Signal Corps and as a member of its examining board. Much of the correspondence is with his brother Will.
    - 1918, 11 folders (Box 3)
  - 1919-1926
    During the 1919-1926 period Reeves was particularly active in the American Political Science Association and was also a leading figure in the Williamsburg Institute.
    - 1919-October 1922, 55 folders (Box 3)
    - November 1922-April 1925, 72 folders (Box 4)
    - May 1925-December 1926, 65 folders (Box 5)
  - 1927-1942
    The papers for 1927-1942 are particularly rich. The correspondence for 1927 includes excellent letters written to his wife and brother (as well as official papers) dealing with his mission as a delegate to the International Commission of Jurists meeting in Buenos Aires. In addition, the correspondence with colleagues in Europe and the Philippines is particularly interesting. There are comments on Mussolini's Italy, the Stavisky affair in France, the early months of the Hitler regime, etc. written by political scientist living in the countries at the time. There is also a large body of correspondence dealing with the placing of refugee scholars in the United States, and illuminating the difficulties associated with this activity.
    - January-June 1927, 18 folders (Box 5)
    - July 1927-March 1929, 85 folders (Box 6)
    - April 1929-1930, 85 folders (Box 7)
    - 1931-1932, 89 folders (Box 8)
    - 1933-April 1935, 95 folders (Box 9)
    - May 1935-September 1937, 92 folders (Box 10)
    - October 1937-July 1940, 96 folders (Box 11)
    - August 1940-1941, undated; 38 folders (Box 12)
- Other Papers
  The series titled Other Papers consists of miscellaneous lectures, research notes, and files relating to professional meetings and conferences.
  - 8th American Scientific Congress, 1940-1941; 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Research notes concerning Hugo Grotius, undated; 10 folders, 1 volume (Box 12)
  - Lectures on international relations, 1894-1928 (Box 12)
  - Lecture concerning the codification of international law, 1922 (Box 12)
  - Paper entitled, "Anglo-German aggression vs. Venezuela in 1902,", 1916 (Box 12)
  - Lectures concerning international society, undated (Box 12)
  - Papers concerning Antarctica, 1930-1939 (Box 12)
  - Historical sketches of the Ann Arbor Scientific Club, 1914; 1932 (Box 12)
  - Speeches, undated (Box 12)
  - Lectures concerning American Government course, undated; 12 folders (Box 13)
  - Lectures concerning American Government course, 1916; 9 folders (Box 13)
  - Notes for Constitutional Law course (Box 13)
  - International Commission of Jurists meeting, 1927 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 13)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1905-1932 (Box 14)
  - Data sheets of nominees for the presidency of the University of Michigan, 1925 (Box 14)
  - Lecture entitled, "The present state of international law,", 1926 (Box 14)
  - Lectures concerning the history of American foreign policy, 1930-1931 (Box 14)
  - Report from the meeting of the International Commission of Jurists, 1927 (Box 14)
  - Diary from the meeting of the International Commission of Jurists, 1927 (Box 14)
  - Booklet from the meeting of the International Commission of Jurists, 1927 (Folder UAm folder)
- Photographs
  - Various, include portraits; photographs of international law classes and meetings; and photographs of camping trips (1911-1913) in Ontario with other University of Michigan faculty members, 4 folders (Box 14)
    (also oversize folder, UAm)
Partial Index to Correspondents and Subjects
Adams, Charles Francis, 1835-1915.
February 20, 1913 and October 24, 1913
Adams, Randolph Greenfield, 1892-1951.
1925-1941 (scattered correspondence, much of it of a routine nature)
Alpena (Mich.)
Letters, Nov. 10 and 20, 1913, from William Comstock on charter revision in Alpena.
American Association of University Professors.
Papers on the founding of the American Association of University Professors, November 1914-January 1915
American Political Science Association.
Letters throughout, especially in 1928 when Reeves was APSA president
Anderson, William P., 1888-
1928, 1930-1933
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.
Correspondence July-Sept. 1926 and Jan. 1927 re the papers of James B. Angell and the biographical sketch of Angell which Reeves was preparing for the Dictionary of American Biography
Angell, James Rowland, 1869-1949.
May 5, 1917, Apr. 12, 1921, Oct. 4, 1926
Automobile travel--United States
An excellent exchange of letters, summer of 1922, between Reeves and his brother Will discussing the hazards and joys of automobile travel including a trip to the East coast and several jaunts in Ohio.
Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937.
Dec. 12, 1930 and June 20, 1934
Bates, Henry Moore, 1869-1949.
Apr. 12, 1915, Sept. 4, 1917, Jan. 21, May 7, and Dec. 10, 20, and 23, 1918, Jan. 14, Apr. 22, and Dec. 5, 1925, Feb. 19, 1926, Mar. 16, 1929, Dec. 1, 1931, Nov. 22, 1933, May 19, 1938, Mar. 9, 1938; also comments about Bates in a letter of Alfred Lloyd to Reeves, Jan. 21, 1918.
Beakes, Samuel Willard, 1861-1927.
Feb. 26, 1915, Feb. 10, 1916
Beal, Junius E. (Junius Emery), 1860-1942.
Feb. 8, 1928, May 13, 1929
Bemis, Samuel Flagg, 1891-1973.
May 7 and 22, 1925, July 29, 1937, June 2, 1941
Blakeslee, George Hubbard, 1871-1954.
Letter, Oct. 10, 1913, and correspondence, 1922-1931, when both were connected with the Institute of International Relations at Williamstown.
Bonner, Campbell, 1876.
Letter, Sept. 13, 1915 discussing Theodore Koch and his librarianship.
Borchard, Edwin Montefiore, 1884-1951.
Jan. 6, June 15, 1923; July 2, Dec. 11, 1925; Mar, Apr. 1931; Dec. 30, 1932; Feb. 2, May 3, 1933; Nov. 1934; Jan. 1935; Jan 2. 1937; Apr. 22, Dec. 1, 1939; May 9, 1940, Apr. 18, 1941
Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.
Mar. 20, 1941
Brown, Everett Somerville, 1886-1964.
Considerable correspondence with Everett Brown, 1920-1927, 1920-1930; good letters from Europe in 1938, especially April 17, 1938; Jan. 27, 1942
Brown, Philip Marshall, 1875-
1913-1941
Brown, Prentiss Marsh, 1889-1973.
Feb. 20, 1937; also comments on Brown in letters to Brown and Everett S. Brown in March 1938
Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.
Nov. 30, 1931
Bryan, William Jennings, 1860-1925.
Typescript, Mar. 4, 1916, of a speech on the U.S. peace mediation offer by William Jennings Bryan, autographed by Bryan.
Burton, Marion LeRoy, 1874-1925.
Letters, March 27 and Nov. 1920; Mar. 7 and Apr. 9, 1923; of Marion LeRoy Burton; also letter, Sept. 3, 1924, of R.T. Crane to Reeves containing candid remarks on Burton.
Carr, Wilbur J. (Wilbur John), 1870-1942.
Sept. and Oct. 1927
Clements, William L. (William Lawrence), 1861-1934.
Dec. 8, 1924, June and July 1925, Feb. 8, 1926, Apr. 27, 1929, Dec. 30, 1931, June 8, 1932, Jan. 7, 1933
Coldwater (Mich.)
Letter, Apr. 7, 1914, from H.H. Barlow to Reeves on Coldwater's election of a charter commission.
Collier, William Miller, 1867-1956.
Letters, Aug. 12, 1927, Oct. 18, 1927, of William Collier, ambassador to Chile.
Comstock, William Alfred, 1877-1949.
Letters, Nov. 10 and 20, 1913, from William Comstock on charter revision in Alpena; letter, Nov. 24, 1915.
Cooley, Charles Horton, 1864-1929.
March 4, 1913, Sept. 29, 1927
Cooley, Mortimer Elwyn, 1855-1944.
Letters in the fall of 1924 containing comments on Cooley's campaign for the Senate.
Cooley, Thomas McIntyre, 1824-1898.
Correspondence between H.M. Bates and Andrew McLaughlin re McLaughlin's doing a new edition of Cooley, Oct. 1907.
Corwin, Edward Samuel, 1878-1963.
Oct. 18, 1916, Feb. 27, 1919, Apr. 22, 1919, Mar. 25, 1921, Feb. 10, 1922, Jan. 15, 1923, Mar.-May, 1923, 1925, 1926, Apr. 1930, May 10, 1930, Aug. 12, 1930, Jan. 19, 1931
Coudert, Frederick R. (Frederick Rene), 1871-
May 15 and 31, 1935; May 26, 1936, Oct. 11, 1937
Courts -- U.S.
Correspondence with Prentiss Brown and Arthur H. Vandenberg, February 20, 1937, re Franklin D. Roosevelt's attempt to reorganize U.S. Supreme Court.
Couzens, James Joseph, 1872-1936.
Apr. 7, 1932 James Couzens.
Crane, Robert Treat, b. 1880.
Sept. 3, 1924 letter containing candid remarks about President Marion Burton.
D'Ooge, Martin Luther, 1839-1915.
Letter, Sept. 13, 1915, of Campbell Bonner commenting fully on the death and last illness of D'Ooge.
Effinger, John Robert, 1869-1933.
Routine correspondence between Reeves and Effinger during Effinger's deanship; also letters, March 20 and July 28, 1928, from Effinger when he was living in Europe.
Eggert, Carl Edgar, 1868-
Letter, Oct. 16, 1917, of Jesse Reeves to his wife and including enclosure, discussing firing of Eggert for purported German sympathies during World War I.
Farrand, Max, 1869-1945.
Dec. 19, 1922, Jan. 10, 1923, Dec. 1936, and May 29 1937
Fascism
1930s letters from colleagues commenting on the rise of fascism and the march toward war
Field, Oliver Peter, 1897-1953.
Feb. 1, 1923 and Feb. 25, 1926
Fite, Emerson David, 1874-1953.
June 5, 1928
Ford, Henry, 1863-1947.
July 7, 1937; also extensive clippings in June 1919 on Ford's libel suit with the Chicago Tribune in which Reeves testified as an expert witness on anarchism.
Ford, Worthington Chauncey, 1858-1941.
Sept. 20, 1936, Oct. 24, 1937
Garfield, Harry Augustus, 1863-1942.
1920-1933
Garner, James Wilford, 1871-1938.
1913-1927; also correspondence on the illness and death of Garner in Dec. 1938.
Gomberg, Moses, 1866-1947.
Apr. 16, 1928, also letter, Aug. 25, 1942, from Gomberg on the occasion of Reeves retirement and discussing their long association.
Guthe, Karl Eugen, 1866-1915.
1913-1914; also letter of Campbell Bonner, Sept. 13, 1915, telling about Guthe's death.
Hart, Albert Bushnell, 1854-1943.
Mar. 17, 1913, Sept. 26, 1921, May 11, 1926.
Hayden, Joseph Ralston, 1887-1945.
Dec. 12, 1917, Jan. 13, 1922, Feb. 13, 1922, May 5, 1922, May 10, 1922, May 14, 1922, Oct. 14, 1922, June 8, 1922, June 21, 1922, Oct. 11, 1922, Nov. 25, 1922, Nov. 27, 1922, Dec. 18, 1922, Jan. 6, 1923, Feb. 2, 1923, June 5, 1923, July 30, 1923, Aug. 13, 1923, Aug. 18, 1925, June 15, 1926, June 26, 1926, Aug. 9, 1926, Jan. 31, 1930, Nov. 26, 1930, Jan. 23, 1931, March 28, 1931, April 14, 1931, Dec. 1933, Feb. 9, 1934, Feb. 12, 1934, April 2, 1934, June 14, 1934, June 26, 1934, July 23, 1934, March 5, 1935, May 12, 1935, May 20, 1935, Feb. 3, 1942, Jan. 26, 1943.
Hays, Will H. (Will Harrison), 1879-1954.
Nov. 17, 1920
Hershey, Amos Shartle, 1867-1933.
July 24, 1928
Hinsdale, Mary L.
1917
Hobbs, William Herbert, 1864-1952.
Mar. 3, 1922 to Claude Van Tyne containing pungent comments on Hobbs.
Hudson, Manley Ottmar, 1886-
ca. 1928-1937
Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948.
1923; also letter, Jan. 25, 1924, appointing Reeves a delegate to conference on codification of International Law.
Hull, Cordell, 1871-1955.
July 25, 1924, Oct. 25, 1939
Huntington, E. V. (Edward Vermilye), 1874-1952.
Long letter, and other correspondence in 1928, on apportionment.
Hutchins, Harry B. (Harry Burns), 1847-1930.
Apr. 1910, 1913-1915
Jameson, J. Franklin (John Franklin), 1859-1937.
ca. 1913-1922, Apr. 7, 1936
Johnson, Allan Chester, 1881-1955.
May 12, 1920; Apr. 6, 10, 15, 1926; Jan. 10, 1927; Sept. 20, 1928; Feb. 18 and March 18, 1929
Kellogg, Frank B. (Frank Billings), 1856-1937.
June 20, 1928 to Reeves appointing him a member of the cooperating committee on the 7th American Scientific Congress.
Kelsey, Francis W. (Francis Willey), 1858.
Nov. 2, 1913, Jan. 17, 1914, Nov. 2, 1914, May 22, 1919, Aug. 1919, Dec. 1919; also correspondence concerning Grotius' study in 1921; also correspondence, 1922-1926
Kenyon College.
Correspondence between Reeves and his brother Will who was a professor of English at Kenyon from 1900 to 1942.
Knudsen, William S., 1879-1948.
July 7, 1938
Koch, Theodore Wesley, 1871-1941.
1914, 1915, Nov. 6 and 8, 1916, 1921, 1923, 1924, May 8, 1925, 1928, 1929, and 1936; also correspondence about Koch's dismissal from Michigan in correspondence of Sept. 1915.
Korff, S. A., (Sergei Aleksandrovich), baron, 1876-1924.
Mar. 7, June 6, Sept. 28, 1922; Jan. 1, Apr. 3 and May 19, 1923; Jan. 30, 1924
Korzybski, Alfred, 1879-1950.
Feb. 24, 1923
Kraus, Edward Henry, 1875-
1913 on routine university business
Laksi, Harold Joseph, 1893-1950.
Apr. 29, 1926; copy of a letter of Oct. 1926, attached to letter of Jan. 13, 1927; Apr. 29, 1933, June 26, 1934; also comments on and quotations of Laski in a letter of July 6, 1936, by Thomas Heneman, one of his students.
Latane, John Holladay, 1869-1932.
1913-1928.
Leacock, Stephen, 1869-1944.
Nov. 14, 1920
Little, Clarence C. (Clarence Cook), 1888.
March 29, 1927, March 26, 1928, Apr. 16, 1928; also free comments on Little in a letter, Apr. 28, 1927, of Robert T. Crane; also papers on his acceptance of the U. of M. presidency, July 1925.
Lloyd, Alfred H. (Alfred Henry), 1864-1927.
Routine official correspondence with Lloyd during his deanship; also comments on his death in the correspondence for June 1927.
McLaren, Walter Wallace.
1929-1931
McLaughlin, Andrew Cunningham, 1861-1947.
Feb. and Dec. 1917 re war and prewar diplomacy; also letters, Oct. 13, 1921 and Jan. 29, 1923; also among Reeves papers for Oct. 1907, is correspondence between H.M. Bates and McLaughlin re a new edition of Cooley.
McLeod, Clarence John, 1895-1959.
Apr. 10, 1926
Merriam, Charles Edward, 1874-1953.
December 11, 1922 and April 30, 1926
Michener, Earl C. (Earl Cory), 1876-1957.
Jan. 11, 1923, Feb. 11, 1928, Apr. 9, 1928, Apr. 1, 1932, Feb. 22, 1937, March 8, 1938
Michigan School of Religion.
Plans for the future of the Michigan School of Religion in the papers of June 9, 1927.
Munro, William Bennett, 1875-1957.
1921, 1925-1926, March 1928
Murfin, James Orin, 1875-1940.
March 12, 1928
Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949.
Aug. 10 and Dec. 3, 1935, May 4, 1937, and Jan. 29, 1940; also excellent comments on the work habits and personality of Murphy in a letter, Feb. 9, 1934, of Hayden to Reeves.
Murrow, Edward R.
1934, Jan. 22 and 25, May 10 and 23, 1935, about displaced persons
Newberry, Truman Handy, 1864-1945.
Apr. 26, 1922 discussing the soldier's bonus
Ogg, Frederic Austin, 1878-1951.
1917-1934.
Panama Canal.
Full descriptions of work on the canal in letters, 1897, of Reeves to his brother.
Perkins, Dexter, 1889-
Feb. 14, 1926
Philippines--History--1898-1946
Correspondence, especially with Joseph Hayden, 1922-1923, 1926, 1930-1931, 1933-1934
Pollock, James Kerr, 1898-
1921-1922, 1925, June 4, 1927, Jan. 29, 1928, Jan. 1929.
Presidents--United States--Election--1904.